Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
When Captain Okita fell ill, I took command.
Do you remember that ?
Yes.
I lost eight crewmen because of my
decision to prioritize rationalism back then.
Deputy Commander…
An analytic mind is the strongest
weapon, but it has limitations.
Don’t you think so ?
That’s…
Captain Okita’s decisiveness was beyond reason.
Likewise, only someone who can go beyond
rationalism is suitable to command the Yamato.
Tactical Commander Kodai, I want to entrust command of the ship to you this time.
I want you to be the acting captain.
You're the only one who is suitable for the job.
Our men should reach the dock any minute now.
In the worst case scenario, the crew might lock
themselves inside the Yamato with the intention to revolt.
We can't find the Yamato.
What ?
The Yamato is right on our monitor.
They must have hacked the surveillance camera.
When did they…
Check inside the dome.
Find their location.
No heat signature.
There's no sign of its departure.
Underground city…
What did you just say ?
The old underground city.
The dock is connected to it.
Give me a visual of the lower tier of the dock.
Cam data on screen.
Where are they ?
Damn them…
Don’t be too rough.
They're the heroes who saved Earth.
Captain Okita, I know what to do this time…
…but I’m afraid…
…afraid of myself for resorting
to using the wave motion gun.
I can still shut down the circuit and disable it.
That would be the right thing to do since we're leaving Earth in protest against the government's policy.
But what if I end up losing
crew members because of it…?
What will I do…?
Kodai, show your resolve.
Captain !
We've detected a ship southwest of the glass dome.
It’s the Kirishima.
W...what ?
Why is a retired ship…?
Who's operating it ?
It’s begun.
We should go, regardless of who
the person is, or where they are.
Is this the only option left, Kodai ?
This way. Hurry.
They're descending into the old underground city.
Send our team in there.
Search throughout the remains of the last great war.
Serizawa !
Once all of them are aboard the Yamato, I'll talk to them.
But…
Don't make a move.
I won't allow any killing.
I understand, but we have to suppress them.
If they ignore you and try to launch the Yamato, then…
Here they come.
Yamazaki !
Kamo, Yoshida, hurry up. Pops is waiting.
Yes, sir.
We don't have enough time for tuning,
and our preparations are inadequate.
But we must launch the Yamato no matter what.
Aye, sir.
The combat satellite…
If it continues getting closer,
the Yamato will be within range.
Are they going to use it ?
We're a ship of rebels.
The chamber is warming up,
but the controls are sensitive.
Ohta, are you ready to steer the ship ?
If he was coming, he would be here already.
So, Shima is…
Every person’s different.
How is it going ?
HQ has mobilized the combat satellite.
Incoming message from HQ.
Put it on the main panel.
I’m Todou Heikuro, the Chief of the Earth Defense Force.
Distinguished crew of the Yamato, who accomplished an unprecedented journey, I want you to listen.
We were saved by Iscandar in the past.
Broadcast this throughout the ship.
That’s why you’re convinced that you
must respond to the voice asking for help.
Wha…? Okay.
I understand how you feel.
But think about it.
We only received a mysterious transmission.
Nothing's been confirmed yet.
You're being too hasty.
The Yamato is a powerful weapon.
If you carelessly get involved in a conflict in
an unknown place, that might endanger Earth.
Nobody wants that kind of future.
It's not too late.
Hand over the Yamato,
and surrender immediately.
Everyone, be courageous and…
Chief, Acting Captain Susumu Kodai here.
I'll give you five minutes.
Everyone, listen carefully.
You just heard the reality.
What the Chief said was right.
But, the Yamato will depart as scheduled.
We must go as long as
there's someone who needs our help.
It's not out of a sense of responsibility, but because it's my hope for how the people of Earth should act.
Leave the ship if you are uncertain.
Whether you leave or stay, it’s up to you.
Acting Captain, you’re way too serious.
We all know what to do.
We lived under the same roof.
This is the engine room. No one’s leaving.
No one’s leaving the tactical team.
Good.
Logistics section, no one’s leaving.
Information section is good to go.
Tech section’s confirmed everyone’s wishes.
Navigation section…
Navigation section, everyone’s present.
Prepare for take off.
Ohta, I’ll steer the ship.
Don’t wreck it.
The control room !
We can't access the dock's control system.
We can't inject water.
Close all the bottom hatches to block any access.
Acting Captain, what should we do ?
Message from Engineer Yamazaki.
Put it on the main panel.
The dock's main system was destroyed.
Not only can we not inject water,
but the gate and gantry locks are inoperable.
But if the sub control room is intact, we can transfer control of the water and lock system to the Yamato.
That means…
Someone has to go there and
manually activate and transfer the system.
That’s right.
Acting Captain, assemble a task force.
I understand, Mr. Yamazaki.
Take Hoshina and Kiryu, and go
there to activate the sub system.
Yes, sir !
Nanbu, I authorize the use of weapons.
Give our task force support.
Okay.
Make sure you don’t hit anybody.
I know.
Weapons are online ! Take cover !
Don’t damage the underground dock.
The power is minimum.
It began shooting. Pull back.
Be careful.
You bet.
Let’s go.
Three crew members left the
ship and are heading somewhere.
Follow and capture them !
Right over there.
Hurry ! Go !
They don’t seem to be escaping.
They fired back.
Hoshina !
Misaki, wait !
It’s activated.
We can transfer control to the Yamato.
Get out !
This is Hoshina in the sub control room.
Water system is activated.
I'm sending the control program to the Yamato.
Here it comes.
Control program transfer confirmed.
Unable to secure the Yamato.
Starting the sub engine.
They've started the launch sequence.
Everyone, evacuate.
The water level is passing
the side observation rooms.
Keep the hatch open.
Don't close it until everyone's back.
Let’s hurry.
With the water rising at this rate,
we won't be able to get back to the ship.
Don't move !
A few men are still over there !
Mr. Yamazaki, we don’t have time.
Hoshina.
The water’s reached here.
This floor isn't safe.
The water’s rising too fast.
It’s dangerous here.
What should we do ?
If they wait for us, the Yamato
won’t be able to take off.
Hoshina !
Hoshina, this way !
Saijo, are you okay ?
It’s dangerous here. Get back.
But Yamazaki and the others…
We have to close this hatch.
They can still use the upper one.
Yamazaki, Hoshina, Kiryu…
Water level has reached the rear hatch.
Closing the water tight doors.
Dispatch a retrieval team to the rear hatch.
Please increase the water fill rate.
Yamazaki, Kiryu, Misaki, and Hoshina
will see the Yamato off from here.
Hoshina, Mr. Yamazaki…
I’m sure the Yamato will successfully
complete this journey without us.
We’ll wait for your safe return.
The four of us are proud to
help start the Yamato's new journey.
Mr. Yamazaki…
Thank you.
Water level is passing the bridge.
Water injection complete.
Release the gantry locks.
All hands, maintain Class-1 battle stations.
Ahead slow, 0.5.
Open the gate.
Yamato is entering the departure corridor.
The Yamato has entered the sea.
We have no other choice.
Get the combat satellite ready for attack.
Send power to the wave motion engine.
Sub engine, increase from
second to third combat speed.
30 seconds until first space knot.
Is he…
Wave motion engine cylinder safety valve open.
Five minutes until wave motion engine ignition.
Shima, if only you were here…
Wave motion engine pressure rising.
Energy charge 90 percent.
As soon as we reach the surface,
ignite the wave motion engine and climb.
Sub engine, maximum combat speed.
Elevation 40 degrees.
Two minutes to surface.
Wave motion engine pressure rising.
Energy charge 100 percent.
Two minutes until wave motion engine ignition.
Well done, Kodai.
Shima.
Sorry for being late.
Shima…
Shima.
We’ll talk later.
Ten seconds until flywheel activation.
One minute to surface.
Current sub engine output is maximum.
Wave motion engine energy charge 120 percent.
Activating flywheel.
Ten seconds until wave motion engine ignition.
Five…
Four…
Three…
Two…
One…
Engaging flywheel for ignition.
Yamato, take off.
Elevation 20 degrees. All systems, nominal.
Deploy wings for atmospheric flight.
Seven thermo-nuclear reactions at 1 o’clock.
Distance 5600km, elevation 27.
Nanbu, get main turrets 1 and 2 ready.
Seven targets, trajectory input complete.
Main turrets ready to fire.
Fire !
Okita’s children are leaving.
That's it. They've crossed the line.
I’ll stop the Yamato for the honor
of the Earth Defense Force.
Episode 4
Take off for the Unknown!
Tawamureru yuragu tsuki no kagami
The reflection of the moon is blurry and capricious
Kodai Susumu:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Enomoto Isami:
Kiryu Mikage:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Ono Daisuke
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Tsuda Kenjiro Tsuda
Nakamura Eriko
Tsuchida Hiroshi
Misaki Yuria:
Saijo Miki:
Hirata Hajime:
Hoshina Toru:
Kitano Tetsuya:
Kamo Kimihiko:
Yoshida Mitsuru:
Kishida Yu:
Okita Juso:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Todou Heikuro:
Assault Force Leader:
Operator A:
Operator B:
Uchida Aya
Moriya Satomi
Ise Fumihide
Takagi Motoki
Kijima Ryuichi
Sunseki Kazuhiro
Kasai Kengo
Torita Yuji
Sugao Takayuki
Genda Tessho
Kojima Toshihiko
Fujinuma Kento
Yano Masaaki
Nokubi Naoko
Kokoro tokasu yuubina kami no itazura
Graceful God's mischief mesmerizes my heart
Uchi ni himeta awai omoide ni
There's a faint memory hidden within
Iki wo fukikomu no michite yukumade
Breathe life into it until it's full
Hibiku anata no mune no kodou wo
I hear a heartbeat echoing through
Watashi hitori janai
I am not alone
Saewataru sora ni inori
I pray to the wide open sky
Atarashii ichinichi no maku ga aketeyuku
The curtain opens on a brand new day
Preview
I'll secure the Yamato no matter the outcome.
They’re coming ! Class-1 battle stations !
Please hold on.
Release camouflage.
Fire !
Side depth-charge launchers, get ready.
Contact with the Andromeda in ten seconds !
Episode 05
Face off ! Yamato vs Andromeda